

Paul Lehn

Fort Lauderdale, FI 33301

(803) 369-5584

✓ pmlehn@gmail.com www.PaulLehn.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated Mobile Application Developer adept at creating and managing apps and solutions for clients ranging from small startups to the US Dept. of Defense. Interests and skills include mobile application development specializing in iOS, website development, and database management. Driven, career-oriented engineer with more than 10 years of experience

SKILLS

- Application development (Swift, UIKit, SwiftUI, CocoaPods/SPM, RESTful API integration, gRPC, XCTest, XCUITest)
- Managing CI/CD pipelines (fastlane, CircleCI, Github Actions)
- Website development (HTML, CSS, Javascript)
- Database Management (SQL, MySQL, Firestore, Parse Server)

- Version-control (Git, Github, Bitbucket)
- Software/IDEs (Xcode, Android Studio, Visual Studio Code, DataGrip, Sourcetree, Postman, Proxyman, Marvel, Figma)
- Training and mentoring
- Spoken Languages: English, Croatian

WORK HISTORY

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

04/2021 to CURRENT

Updater | New York, NY

Worked with a mid-sized team managing the suite of Updater apps that focus on end-to-end solutions for the moving industry. Major projects include:

<u>Dolly Customer</u> and <u>Dolly Helper</u> (On-demand moving service)

- Full redesign and refactors of existing code bases.
- Feature development with A/B tested rollouts.
- Built out a robust CI/CD pipeline for the mobile team

HSC Go

Greenfield SwiftUI app that drives moves of U.S. Armed Forces, Department of Defense (DoD) civilians, and their families.

- Used the latest in the SwiftUI and Combine frameworks to implement a modern, well tested, and future-proof codebase
- Implemented over 500 stated requirements by the government involving security, privacy, offline capabilities, and analytics.

PRINCIPAL APPLICATION DEVELOPER

Reatro Ventures, LLC. | Boca Raton, FL

Lead developer of mobile applications for Reatro Ventures, working with a close-knit team to implement ideas and bring them to life on the app store. Some examples of apps released were Emvite (Emoji based social media), Leart Mac & Cheese (Fast casual restaurant), PickleJar (Live performance tipping). Involved in the full app development lifecycle, including:

- Direct communication with clients to understand their vision
- Helped clients map and plan out app concepts
- Worked closely with the design team, wireframing and prototyping
- Developed, tested, and launched apps on the App Store
- Released updates and provided ongoing support

LEAD IOS DEVELOPER

08/2016 to 12/2017

MojiLife Inc. | Boca Raton, FL

Managed, implemented, tested, and deployed all versions of a highly complex 3-1 Social Media app. The app combines Social, Professional, and Dating accounts into one clean, easy to use experience.

- Developed complex features such as creating and editing profiles, companies, linking and importing posts from Facebook/Instagram, Tinder-like dating interface, full blown chat, push notifications, etc.
- Integrated with our custom API as well as with Google Places, Maps, Instagram, and Facebook.

LEAD IOS DEVELOPER (CONTRACTOR)

08/2015 to 05/2016

Npute Inc. | West Palm Beach, Florida, FL

Developed a high end classifieds iOS app that plugs into the "Listy" network. Users can post new listings of items they wish to sell as well as find items they may be interested in buying.

- Implemented features such as map integration, optional Craigslist feed, and secure Chat.
- The app was built with Swift, using MapKit, custom API, and open source libraries imported via CocoaPods.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / IOS DEVELOPER

08/2014 to 06/2015

Bass Egg Inc. | West Palm Beach, Florida

Developed software for Bass Egg, completing projects as assigned. Some of these projects include:

- Android app designed for tablets used in trade show display booths.
- iOS application to connect with Bass Egg speaker. This Included low level audio manipulation and equalization using CoreAudio and AVPlayer.
- Google Docs script for automating email survey management.
- Web app for customizing/purchasing Bass Eggs.

WEB DEVELOPER

04/2013 to 06/2013

Forte Interactive | West Palm Beach, FL

 Developed and Implemented websites, where I received Photoshop files from the design department and converted them into fully functional websites. This involved slicing out individual layers of the documents and using HTML, CSS, and Javascript to position them correctly and make them function exactly as expected.

- Fast paced environment with multiple websites being worked on at once. Most websites were for nonprofit organizations.
- Example work: http://www.myamicimarket.com/

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science | Computer Science **Palm Beach Atlantic University, West Palm Beach, Florida** Honors: 12/2014

- Computer Science Club Treasurer
- Community Service
- Winner of the Palm Beach Atlantic computer game programming contest for 2012

High School Diploma

05/2011

The American International School of Zagreb, Zagreb, Croatia *IB Diploma (International Baccalaureate), GPA 3.7* Honors:

- Student Government
- Intramural Basketball
- Community Service

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

REFERENCES

Matthew Hamilton Columbus, Ohio
Director of Mobile and Int Tech at Updater.
(330) 933 2466, matthew.hamilton@updater.com
Matt Pappas Boca Raton, Florida
Creative Director at Reatro Ventures, LLC.
(727) 534 5505, matt.pappas@reatro.com
Craig Henderson Boca Raton, Florida
Chief Technology Officer at Mojilife Inc.
(561) 350 8840

Dr. Kenneth Pembamotto West Palm Beach, Florida Dean of Computer Science at Palm Beach Atlantic University (561) 707 2067, kenneth.pembamotto@pba.edu